grade_5_part_1 = {
    "Decimal place value": [
        {
            "Decimal place value intro": {
            "Definition": "Decimals are a way of writing numbers that include parts of a whole. They are written with a decimal point to separate the whole number from the fractional part.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "What value does the 7 represent in the number 94.087?",
                        "Answer": "0.007",
                        "Type": "Decimal",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Comparing decimals": {
            "Definition": "We can compare decimals by starting with the whole number parts. If they are different, the larger whole number makes the larger decimal. If the whole number parts are the same, compare the digits after the decimal point from left to right until you find a difference.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Gus is measuring earth worms that he digs up in his backyard. The worm he found in the garden was 8.9 cm long. The worm he found under the porch was 9 cm long. Which worm is longer?",
                        "Answer": "The worm from underneath the porch.",
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Decimals in expanded form": {
            "Definition": "Expanded form is a way to write numbers by adding the value of its digits.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Let's write 3.405 in expanded form.",
                        "Answer": "3 + 4/10 + 0/100 + 5/1000.",
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Decimals in written form": {
            "Definition": "Written form is a way to write numbers using only words.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Let's write 3.405 in written form.",
                        "Answer": "3 ones + 405 thousands.",
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Rounding decimals": {
            "Definition": "Rounding decimals to the nearest tenth can be fun. We can identify the tenths place in the given decimal, 9.564. Then we can look at the digit to the right of the tenths place to determine whether to round up or down. In this case, the answer is to round up to 9.6.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Some queen bumblebees weigh up to 0.85 grams. Round the weight to the nearest gram.",
                        "Answer": "1 gram.",
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
     "Add decimal":[
        {
            "Estimate with adding decimals": {
            "Definition": "Estimating with adding decimals means finding an approximate answer by rounding the decimals to the nearest whole number, tenth, or hundredth.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Estimate the sum of 12.34 and 5.67.",
                        "Answer": "If we want to estimate the sum of 12.34 and 5.67, we can round both numbers to the nearest tenth: 12.34 \approx 12.3 and 5.67 \approx 5.7.\nThen, we can add the rounded numbers: 12.3 + 5.7 = 18.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Add decimals with different number of decimal places":{
            "Definition": "To add decimals and whole numbers that have different number of decimal places, we can use zeros as placeholders to make them have the same number of decimal places.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Add 51 and 48.2.",
                        "Answer": "We can use 0 as placeholder for the first decimal place of 51, then try to add as normal: 51.0 + 48.2 = 99.2.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
    "Subtract decimal":[
        {
            "Subtract decimals with different number of decimal places":{
            "Definition": "To subtract decimals and whole numbers that have different number of decimal places, we can use zeros as placeholders to make them have the same number of decimal places.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "You run a lap in 2.3 minutes and your friend runs it in 2.42 minutes.\nHow much time do you finish faster than your friend?",
                        "Answer": "We need to subtract 2.42 from 2.3.\nWe can use 0 as placeholder for the second decimal place of 2.3, then try to subtract as normal: 2.42 - 2.30 = 0.12.\nSo the answer is 0.12 minute.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
    "Add and subtract fractions":[
        {
            "Common denominators":{
            "Definition": "When fractions have the same denominator, we say they have common denominators. One way to find a common denominator for two (or more!) fractions is to list the multiples of each denominator until we find the smallest multiple they have in common.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "In his garden, Trey plants carrot seeds 1/4 in deep and bean seeds 7/8 in deep.\nWhat equivalent expression (using common denominator of two fractions) can be used to find how much deeper Trey planted the bean seeds than the carrot seeds?",
                        "Answer": "A common multiple of 4 and 8 is 8.\nSo we can obtain the following equivalent expression: 7/8 - 2/8.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Adding and subtracting fractions with unlike denominators":{
            "Definition": "To add and subtract them, we have to find a common denominator. Then, we rewrite them as improper fractions with that denominator. Lastly, we add or subtract the two improper fractions together and simplify the result if needed.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Johnny and Elizabeth were playing a video game and trying to get all of the treasure boxes. Johnny got 7/3 treasure boxes. Elizabeth got 14/9 treasure boxes. Together, Johnny and Elizabeth got how many treasure boxes?",
                        "Answer": "In total, Johnny and Elizabeth got 7/3 + 14/9 = 21/9 + 14/9 = 35/9 treasure boxes.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Adding and subtracting mixed numbers":{
            "Definition": "Mixed numbers are numbers that contain both a whole number and a fraction.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Add two mixed numbers 5 7/8 and 1 1/3.",
                        "Answer": "The two mixed numbers written in fraction form are 47/8 and 4/3. Adding them together we get 47/8 + 4/3 = 173/24.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
    "Multi-digit multiplication and division":[
        {
            "Standard algorithm for multiplication":{
            "Definition": "The standard algorithm for multiplication involves breaking one of the numbers down into its place values, multiplying each place value by the other number, and then adding the results together.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "What is the area of a rectangle with height 15 and width 37?",
                        "Answer": "The area of the rectangle is 15 * 37 = 555.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Estimate multi-digit multiplication":{
            "Definition": "One way to estimate is to round each number to the nearest ten, hundred, or thousand (depending on the size of the numbers) and then multiply the rounded numbers together.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Estimate 7288 * 96.",
                        "Answer": "The approximations for 7288 and 96 are 7000 and 100.\nSo 7288 * 96 would be about 700,000.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Estimate multi-digit division":{
            "Definition": "For division, we can estimate the dividend and divisor to the nearest ten, hundred, or thousand (depending on the size of the numbers) and then divide the rounded numbers.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Estimate 314 / 27.",
                        "Answer": "The approximations for 314 and 27 are 310 and 30.\nSo 314 / 27 would be about 310 / 30 \approx 10.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Remainders in division":{
            "Definition": "The remainder is the amount left over when you divide one number by another and the division doesn't come out evenly.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Calculate 2895 / 229. Write your answer as a whole number and remainder.",
                        "Answer": "The answer is 12 with remainder 147.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ]
}

grade_5_part_2 = {
    "Multiply fractions":[
        {
            "Fraction multiplication":{
            "Definition": "To multiply two fractions together, we multiply the corresponding numerator and denominator, then simplify the answer.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "2/3 of the doughnuts in a box have frosting and 1/2 of the doughnuts with frosting have sprinkles.\nWhat fraction of the doughnuts in the box have frosting and sprinkles?",
                        "Answer": "The fraction of the doughnuts have both frosting and sprinkles is 2/3 * 1/2 = 2/6 = 1/3.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Multiplying mixed numbers":{
            "Definition": "Mixed numbers are numbers that contain both a whole number and a fraction.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "A punch bowl had 2 1/2 liters of juice in it. Liam drank 1/3 of the juice in the bowl.\nHow many liters of juice did Liam drink?",
                        "Answer": "Liam drank 2 1/2 * 1/3 = 5/2 * 1/3 = 5/6 liters of juice.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
    "Divide fractions":[
        {
            "Fraction division":{
            "Definition": "When we divide fractions, we can use the reciprocal of the divisor (the fraction we are dividing by) to multiply instead.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "A baker is making biscuits. She has 6 kg of dough. Each biscuit is made with 1/5 kg of dough. How many biscuits can she make?",
                        "Answer": "She can make 6 / (1/5) = 6 * 5 = 30 biscuits.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
    "Multiply decimals":[
        {
            "Multiplying decimals":{
            "Definition": "When we multiply decimals by decimals, we multiply the two numbers as if they were whole numbers. We then count the total number of digits after the decimal point in both numbers, and place the decimal point in the product so that there are the same number of digits after the decimal point.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Multiply 5.9 and 3.3.",
                        "Answer": "By multiplying 59 and 33, we obtain 1947.\nBy estimating 5.9 * 3.3 \approx 6 * 3 = 18, we need to place the decimal in 1947 to get a product close to 18. So our answer is 19.47.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
    "Divide decimals":[
        {
            "Divide whole numbers to get a decimal quotient":{
            "Definition": "When we divide one whole number by another, we're trying to break the first number into equal-sized chunks. But other times, the first number can't be divided evenly by the second. For example, if we divide 11 by 4, we can only divide it into two chunks of four, with three left over. We can express this as a mixed number (2 3/4) or as a decimal (2.75). The decimal represents the part of the chunk that we couldn't divide evenly.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Express your answer as a decimal: 63 / 12.",
                        "Answer": "Split 63 into 60 and 3: 63/12 = (60 + 3)/12.\nBreak into two fractions: 60/12 + 3/12 = 5 + 1/4 = 5.25.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
    "Powers of ten":[
        {
            "Powers of 10":{
            "Definition": "To evaluate a power of 10, we multiply the base (10) by itself the exponent amount of times. The number of zeros in the solution always matches the exponent.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Which power of 10 is equivalent to 10,000?",
                        "Answer": "10,000 has 4 zeros, so 10,000 = 10^4.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Multiplying and dividing with powers of 10":{
            "Definition": "When you multiply a decimal by 10, 100 or 1,000, you're effectively shifting the decimal point to the right. When you divide a decimal by 10, 100 or 1,000, you're effectively shifting the decimal point to the left.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Calculate 889 * 100.",
                        "Answer": "We add 2 zeros into the right of 889 and get 88,900.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
    "Volume":[
        {
            "Volume of rectangular prisms":{
            "Definition": "There are a few different ways we can find the volume of a rectangular prism. We can use unit cubes to fill the prism and count how many we used, or we can multiply the area of the base by the height of the prism.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Erin built a wooden box to hold hay on her farm. The box is 3 m long, 1 m wide, and 1 m high.\nHay costs \$14 per cubic meter.\nHow much will it cost to completely fill the box with hay?",
                        "Answer": "The area of the base is 3 * 1 = 3 m^2.\nThe volume of the box is 3 * 1 = 3 m^3.\nThe total cost is 3 * 14 = 42 dollars.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Decompose figures to find volume":{
            "Definition": "To decompose a figure means to break it down into smaller shapes. We can use this strategy to find the volume of more complicated shapes by breaking them down into shapes we know how to measure.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "I made a fort by connecting two boxes.\nThe first box is 5 meters long, 9 meters wide, and 9 meters high.\nThe second box is 3 meters long, 8 meters wide, and 2 meters high.\nHow many cubic meters of space does my fort have?",
                        "Answer": "The volume of the first box is 5 * 9 * 9 = 405 m^3.\nThe volume of the second box is 3 * 8 * 2 = 48 m^3.\nSo my fort have 405 + 48 = 453 cubic meters.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
    "Coordinate plane":[
        {
            "Intro to the coordinate plane":{
            "Definition": "The coordinate plane is a two-dimensional grid that is used to graph points and lines. A coordinate plane has four sections called quadrants. Quadrant one (QI) is in the upper right-hand corner of the coordinate plane, Quadrant two (QII) is in the upper left-hand corner, Quadrant three (QIII) is in the lower left-hand corner, and Quadrant four (QIV) is in the lower right-hand corner.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Lyn graphed the locations of several places on her school playground on the coordinate plane shown below.\nBEGIN PLOT:\nDraw('Slide', (4, 9))\nDraw('Monkey bars', (2, 7))\nDraw('Carousel', (0, 2))\nDraw('Rope climb', (4, 5))\nDraw('Swings', (9, 4))\nEND PLOT.\nThere is also a water fountain halfway between the slide and the rope climb.\nAt what coordinates should Lyn graph the water fountain?",
                        "Answer": "The water fountain is at the coordinate (4, 7).",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
    "Algebraic thinking":[
        {
            "Number patterns":{
            "Definition": "To find relationships between two patterns, we look for similarities or differences. For example, we might notice that the pattern 2x+1 always gives us an odd number, while the pattern 2x always gives us an even number.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Which rule describes the relationship between the x- and y-coordinates in the sequence: (1, 6), (4, 15), (6, 21)?",
                        "Answer": "Multiply x by 3, then add 3 to the result to get y.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
    "Converting units of measure": [
        {
            "Converting metric units":{
            "Definition": "To convert metric units, we use the prefixes: kilo-, hecto-, deka-, deci-, centi-, and milli-. Each prefix corresponds to a certain power of ten. For example, 1 kilometer (km) is equal to 1,000 meters (m), and 1 centimeter (cm) is equal to 0.01 meters (m).",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Jim has 19,700 g of sand in his sandbox. He brings home another 6,300 g of sand from the beach to add to his sandbox. How many kilograms of sand does Jim have in his sandbox now?",
                        "Answer": "We can convert 19,700 g and 6,300 g into 19.7 kg and 6.3 kg correspondingly.\nAdding the two, we obtain the answer: 19.7 + 6.3 = 26 kg.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Converting US Customary units":{
            "Definition": "To convert US customary units, we need to know the relationships between the different units. For example, there are 12 inches in 1 foot, 3 feet in 1 yard, and 16 ounces in 1 pound.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Xan and Katie are twins. Xan weighs 6 pounds 9 ounces, and Katie weighs 8 pounds 1 ounce. What is the difference, in ounces, between Xan and Katie's weight?",
                        "Answer": "Xan's weight is: 6 * 16 + 9 = 105 ounces.\nKatie's weight is: 8 * 16 + 1 = 129 ounces.\nThe difference in weight between them is: 129 - 105 = 24 ounces.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
    "Properties of shapes":[
        {
            "Classifying triangles":{
            "Definition": "When we classify triangles by sides, we look at the lengths of the sides. For example, an equilateral triangle has three sides of equal length, while an isosceles triangle has two sides of equal length. When we classify triangles by angles, we look at the size of the angles. For example, a right triangle has one right angle, while an acute triangle has three angles that are all less than 90 degrees.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "A triangle RST has three sides all have length 8 m. Is it a right triangle, an acute triangle, or an obtuse triangle?",
                        "Answer": "The triangle RST is an acute triangle.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Quadrilaterals":{
            "Definition": "A quadrilateral is a shape with four sides. There are many types of quadrilaterals, but some common ones include squares, rectangles, rhombuses, and trapezoids.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Name the special type of the quadrilateral ABCD that is shown in the following plot.\nBEGIN PLOT:\nDraw('A', (0, 0))\nDraw('B', (3, 1))\nDraw('C', (0, 2))\nDraw('D', (3, 3))\nEND PLOT.",
                        "Answer": "The quadrilateral ABCD is a parallelogram.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ]
}